(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-03T13:49:36.030223",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ここはとある世界のお花屋さん
Here is a flower shop in a certain world.
そんなお花屋には七色に輝く一輪のお花がいました
In that flower shop, there was a single flower
shining in seven colors.
彼女はこの花屋が大好きでした
She loved this flower shop.
花屋では毎日たくさんのお花たちが美しく咲き誇ります
Every day in the shop, many flowers
bloomed magnificently.
そんなお花たちを見て笑顔になるお客さん
Customers would smile looking at those flowers,
彼女はその笑顔が何よりも大好きでした
and she loved those smiles more than anything.
でもここは お花屋さん
But this is a flower shop.
そんな咲き誇ったお花たちも 一輪 また一輪と お客さんと一緒に 旅立っていきました
Those fully bloomed flowers, one by one,
departed together with the customers.
笑顔で旅立っていくお花と お客さんを見て 彼女はとても幸せでした
Seeing flowers and customers depart with smiles,
she was very happy.
アレ、でも、だけど私は...
Huh? But, but as for me...
今日も笑顔で旅立っていく花たち
Today too, flowers depart with smiles.
「あのお花は大きくて綺麗だな...」「あの子の色は素敵だな...」
"That flower is so big and pretty..."
"That child's color is wonderful..."
「アレ？私って...どんな花なんだろう、？」
"Huh? What kind of flower... am I?"
自分の魅力がわからくなってしまった彼女は
Unable to understand her own charm anymore,
ついに自分の色を見失ってしまいました
she finally lost sight of her own color.
そう簡単な祈りだった
It was such a simple prayer.
端から段々と消える感嘆
Admiration gradually fading from the start.
今から綴軸が上がるから
The curtain is about to rise, so
静かな会場を後にさようなら
say goodbye to the silent venue.
言いかけていた事が一つ消えてまた増えて
Things I started to say vanish and increase again,
背中に後悔さが残る
leaving regret lingering on my back.
従いたい心根を吐き出せぬように詰め込んで
Stuffing away my obedient heart so I can't spit it out,
胸の中が泥のように濁る
my chest grows muddy like sediment.
受け止めたいことが自分さえ抱えられず
Unable to even hold what I want to accept,
持て余したそれを守っている
I'm protecting what I have left over.
霞んだ声はからからに喉を焼いて埋め尽くす
My hazy voice parches my throat and fills it up,
何を言うべきかわからなくて
not knowing what I should say.
感じていたものが遠く放たれていた
What I felt was cast far away.
同じようで違う なんだか違う
It looks the same, yet different, somehow different.
いつまで行こうか どこまで行けるのか
Until when should I go? How far can I go?
定かじゃないなら何を想うのか
If it's uncertain, what am I thinking?
僕らが離れるなら 僕らが迷うなら
If we are to part, if we are to stray,
その度に何回も繋がれるように
so we can connect again and again each time.
ここにいいてくれるなら 離さずにいられたら
If you stay here with me, if we don't let go,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で救われていく
I'm saved by a feeling nobody knows yet.
平和とは消耗を以て代わりに成す
Peace replaces itself with exhaustion.
実際はどうか変わりはなく
In reality, nothing changes at all.
そう簡単な祈りだった
It was such an easy prayer,
端から段々と消える感嘆
admiration gradually fading from the start.
今から緞帳が上がるから
The curtain is about to rise,
静かな会場を後にさようなら
so say goodbye and leave the silent venue.
言いかけていた事が一つ消えてまた増えて
Words I started to say vanish and return,
背中に出る後ろめたさが残る
leaving a lingering guilt upon my back.
従いたい心根を吐き出さないように詰め込んで
Packing away the urge to obey so it won't spill out,
胸の中が濁りのように濁る
my heart muddies up like sediment.
受け止めたい事が自分さえ抱えられず
I can't even hold what I wish to accept,
持て余したそれを守っている
guarding what's left over.
掠んだ声はからからに喉を焼いて埋め尽くす
My hoarse voice burns and fills my dry throat,
何を言うべきか分からなくて
not knowing what I ought to say,
感じていたものが遠く放たれていた
as what I felt was cast far away.
同じ様で違う何なんだ違い
It looks the same yet different—what is the difference?
何時まで行こうか
How long will we go?
何処まで行けるのか
How far can we reach?
定かじゃないなら何を想うのか
If it's uncertain, what do we think?
僕らが離れるなら僕らが迷うなら
If we are to part, if we are to stray,
その度に何回も繋がれる様に
so we can be connected again and again,
ここに居てくれるなら離さないでいられたら
if you stay here, if I could hold on to you,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で救われていく
I am saved by an unknown sensation.
平穏とは消耗を以て代わりに成す
Peace is achieved at the cost of exhaustion,
実際はどうも変わりはなく
though in truth nothing really changes,
享楽とは嘘で成る
and pleasure is built on lies.
「綻ぶ前にここを出て行こうか」と
"Let's leave here before it unravels,"
都合の良い願いを同じ様に同じ様にする
I repeat the self-serving wish just as before.
何処から聞き込こうか何処を見失うか
Where should I listen? What do I lose sight of?
定かじゃないなら此処を動けない
If it's uncertain, I cannot move from here.
僕らが疲れるならこれ以上無いなら
If we grow weary, if there's nothing more,
その度に何回も逃げ出せる様に
so we can escape time and time again,
心が守れるように奪われないように
to protect our hearts, so they won't be stolen,
互いに託して身体を預けてよ
let's entrust each other and surrender our bodies.
君と泣く 君と笑う 君と怒る
Crying with you, smiling with you, getting angry with you,
君と歌う 君と踊る 君と話す
singing with you, dancing with you, talking with you.
何時まで続くんだろうと
Wondering how long it will last,
同じ様に同じ様に呟く
I murmur just the same.
いま忘れないように刻まれた空気を
The air carved into me so I won't forget,
これから何度思い出すのだろう
how many times will I recall it from now on?
僕らだけが
Only us...
僕らが離れるなら 僕らが迷うなら
If we are to part, if we are to stray,
その度に何回も 繋がれる様に
so we can be connected again and again,
ここに居てくれるなら 離さないでいられたら
if you stay here, if I could hold on to you,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で
in an unknown sensation...
僕の生きている全てを確かめて
confirming everything of my life,
正しくそして
correctly and truly.
あっ、ローゼ、ガールズたち、ありがとうー！
Ah, Rosé, girls, thank you so much!
ありがとうで、うわぁ、ありがと、ありがとー！
Thank you, wow, thank you, thank you!
ということで、お待たせ生誕祭の、みんな見えてる？聞こえてる？
And so, thank you for waiting! Can everyone see and hear me?
ホロライブ所属の夜行系ハーフエルフ、アキ・ローゼンタールこと…
Hololive's nocturnal half-elf, Aki Rosenthal...
ん？アキ・ロ…アキ・ローゼン…
Hm? Aki Ro... Aki Rosen...
緊張したけど、もう一回行くね。
I got nervous, let's try that again.
アキ・ローゼンタールです！はろはろはろ、アローナ！
I'm Aki Rosenthal! Hello hello hello, Arona!
はい！アキ・ローゼンタール生誕祭2025へようこそー！
Yes! Welcome to the Aki Rosenthal Birthday Festival 2025!
え、今年のテーマは「Your true colors」とさせていただきまして…
Um, this year's theme is "Your true colors,"
ま、アキ・ローゼンがね、今まで生誕祭でよくやっていたミュージカル形式とは、ま、ちょっと趣向を変えて、ま、違う感じの生誕祭を今年はやってみようかなと思って、いる、ちょっと変わった、また去年と違ったライブにしたいなと思っております。
and unlike the musical style I've often done for past birthday lives, I wanted to try something a bit different this year—a slightly unusual live that feels different from last year.
なんと今年は、いろんなね、ゲストの方がなんと、もりだくさん登場してくれるということなので、ぜひいろんな人を楽しみに待っててね！
And this year, we have tons of amazing guests appearing, so please look forward to meeting everyone!
はい、で、今回の、アキ・ローゼの生誕祭のハッシュタグは、こちら！アキ・ローゼ生誕祭2025こちらのハッシュタグをつけて、ポストなのでじゃんじゃんつぶやいてください！
And the hashtag for this year's birthday festival is right here! Please use "#AkiRosenthalBirthday2025" to post and tweet away!
え？何？アキ・ローゼが可愛すぎてスクショが止まらない？
Eh? What? Aki-rose is too cute and you can't stop taking screenshots?
そうだよね、そうだよね！なんと、気づいた人いるかな？アキ・ローゼ少し、なんか…ちょっと可愛くなってない？
I know, right? Did anyone notice? Does Aki-rose look a little... cuter than usual?
そう、ちょっとねメイクを、いま風にしてみたっていうか。
Yeah, I tried making my makeup a bit more modern.
髪の毛とかもちょっとオイルとかつけて、ツヤツヤにしてみたんだけど、どう？
I put some oil in my hair to make it glossy, how is it?
どう？よく見て、よく見て、アップで、アップで、ちょっと可愛い顔を、ぜひ。
How's that? Look closely, in close-up, please check out my cute face!
そう！ちょっと可愛くなってるでしょ？ま、元から可愛いのは知ってるんだけどね。
Right? I've gotten a bit cuter, haven't I? Well, I know I was cute to begin with!
なんでこういうね、スクショとかいっぺい撮って、あのポストでつぶやいてね、ぜひ盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです！よろしくね！
So please take lots of screenshots like this and post them to hype up the stream! Thank you!
そして、まだまだ！気を抜くなよ！この配信の後、メンバー限定でアフターライブもやる予定なので、そちらもお楽しみに！メンバー登録するなら今だ今だ！今だ今だ今だ今だ…そして…
And there's more! Don't let your guard down yet! After this broadcast, we'll also have a member-exclusive after-live, so look forward to that too! If you're going to join the membership, now's the time! Now, now, now, now... And...
この配信のラストには
For the very last part of this stream...
アキロゼの新曲のお披露目もあるから、最後まで楽しんでいってね！
we have a new song reveal, so please enjoy it until the end!
ということで、次の曲早速いっちゃいましょう！
With that said, let's jump right into the next song!
それでは聞いてください。
Please listen to it.
「青のすみか」
"Ao no Sumika"
どこまでも続くような 青の季節は
In the endless blue season,
四つ並ぶ目の前を 遮るものは何もない
nothing blocks our four eyes lined up ahead.
アスファルト、蝉時雨を反射して
Asphalt reflecting the cicadas' rain,
きみという沈黙が聞こえなくなってくる
the silence that is you becomes unheard.
この日々が色褪せる
These days fade away,
僕と違うきみの匂いを知ってしまっても
even though I know your scent, different from mine,
置き忘れてきた 永遠の底に
left behind at the bottom of eternity,
今でも青が澱んでいる
even now, blue lingers.
今でも青は澄んでいる
even now, blue is clear.
どんな祈りも言葉も 近づけるのに、届かなかった
all my prayers and words came close, but didn't reach you.
まるで、静かな恋のような
It was like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
running down my cheeks, in a summer-colored hue.
きみを呪う言葉が ずっと喉の奥につかえている
The words to curse you are still stuck in my throat.
「また 会える よね」って
Saying, "We'll meet again, right?"
声 にならない 声
A voiceless voice.
昼下がり、じめつく風の季節は
In the afternoon, in the humid breeze season,
想い馳せる まだ何者でもなかった僕らの肖像
we recall the portraits of ourselves when we were still nobodies.
何かもかも分かち合えたはずだった
We should have been able to share everything.
あの日から少しずつ 君と違う僕という呪いが肥えていく
Since that day, the curse of being different from you has grown bit by bit.
ララララ…ララララ…
La-la-la-la, la-la-la-la...
君の笑顔の奥の憂いを見落としたこと、悔やみ尽くして
Regretting that I overlooked the sadness behind your smile,
徒花と咲いて散っていく
blooming and scattering like a flower in vain.
きみにさようなら
Saying goodbye to you.
ララララ…ララララ…
La-la-la-la, la-la-la-la...
今でも青が澱んでいる
Even now, blue lingers.
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, blue is clear.
どんな祈りも言葉も 近づけるのに、届かなかった
All my prayers and words came close, but didn't reach you.
まるで、静かな恋のような
It was like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
running down my cheeks, in a summer-colored hue.
きみを呪う言葉が ずっと喉の奥につかえている
The words to curse you are still stuck in my throat.
「また 会える よね」って
Saying, "We'll meet again, right?"
声 にならない 声
A voiceless voice.
無限に膨張する銀河の星の粒のように 指の隙間を零した
Spilling through the gaps between my fingers like star particles of an expanding galaxy.
はーい、みんな！ありがとー！
Hii, everyone! Thank you so much!
ということで、本日アキロゼ生誕祭、ゲストで出演していただいたのは
With that said, our guest performers who joined us today
シオンさん！そして、ベイドくん！
for Aki's birthday live are Shion-san and Bettel-kun!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you, thank you!
いやー、なんかやっと…
Man, finally...
ははは！
Haha!
歌ったは歌ったんだけど。
I sang it, though.
いや、でもね、
Well...
まあ、歌はね、行けるというか、ね。
Well, singing is...
我々も参加してきましたよ、と。
We've done it before, too.
そうね、そういうのはあるから。
So, there's that.
まあまあまあ、と思ってたんですけど。
Well, that's what we thought, but...
苦労したのはやっぱり踊りじゃないですか。
The hard part was definitely the dancing, wasn't it?
聞いてない？
Haven't you heard?
聞いて...
聞いてない？
Haven't you heard?
いや、踊らされるなんて聞いてない。
I haven't heard about being made to dance!
聞いてません！
We haven't heard anything!
聞いてないよ。
Haven't you heard?
え、でもどう？ダンスレッスンしてやってみてどうよ？
Well, how about doing dance lessons and trying it out?
まあ...
Well...
でも中だってフォーメーションめちゃくちゃでしょ？ニコナナだって。
I mean, the formations were a bit of a mess, though.
まあでも、思ったより面白かったから。
It was way more fun than we thought, right?
まあまあ、結構楽しかったよね。
Well, it was pretty fun, wasn't it?
結構楽しかったけど。
It was pretty fun, though.
「1、2、3」ってやって、
Like, 1, 2, 3...
1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
なんか頭の中で、もうずっとメトロノーム鳴ってるの。
Inside my head, it was like a metronome the whole time.
カチカチカチカチカチ。
"Tap, tap, tap, tap, tap."
でもね、動けてて、先生も褒めてたしね。
Even though I was moving and she praised me, you know.
いや、でもよかったけど、またやりたいかって言われるとちょっと。
Even so, when asked "Do you want to do it again?" I hesitated.
あれ？そんな大変なんだな。
Oh? It's that much trouble?
いや、そう。
Well, yeah.
あのね、大変さ、マジで身にしみたその、やっぱ踊ってる人の、みんな、やっぱこれすごいんだなって。
You know, the heavy duty people really soaked through, and seeing the dancers, like, everyone, "Wow, this is amazing!"
この人ね、本当にすごいっす。
That person really is amazing.
いや、いやそんな、何も、ないよ！
No, no, nothing like that.
ほら、ほら！ほらもう見て今の動き！
Look, look, look! Look at that movement right now!
見て今の動き！そんな、そんなぐるって回れないよ、普通。一般人がやろうとしてみ？
Look at that movement! There's no way you can spin around like that, an ordinary person trying to do it.
こんな、こんなんなんだよ？こんなもんなんだよ、みんな！
Is this, is this all there is? That's all there is, everyone!
その動きやめて！
Stop that movement!
すごいんだって！その動きやめてよ！
It's amazing! Stop that movement!
逆流アップしちゃう。
It'll throw your back out!
マジでその動きやめて。
Seriously, stop that movement.
まあでも、見習わなきゃなんて思いましたね。
Well, you gotta learn the basics, I thought.
だってゲームばっかやってるから、たまには動いたほうがいいんじゃない？
Since we're always playing games, we should move around sometimes.
こっから先はけっこう筋肉あるんだよね。
From here on, it gets into muscle training, right?
そうね、動かしてるし、毎日もうこんなマウスぶんぶんですからね。
Well, yeah, we're moving, and every day our mouse is clicking like crazy, so.
これできない動きあるって言われてたんだっけ？
And they told us there are some movements we just can't do.
えっとね、なんだっけな？ピンって手伸ばせないじゃん、これが。
What was it? You can't stretch your fingers out, right?
まあ、伸ばしにくいっすけど。
Well, stretching is pretty difficult though.
これこれができないって、これFPS筋なしですよ。
They say you can't do that if you don't have FPS hands.
FPSフィンガーだ、んだ、手首がね。手首が硬いみたいな。
FPS finger, arm, wrist... The wrists are stiff, right?
ふにゃふにゃ。まあなんか雷遁ふにゃふにゃ。
Fufun, fufun... Raidoken fufun, fufun...
待って、じゃあFPS筋育ってない？
Wait, so you haven't grown FPS hands yet?
いや、俺結構やって...
No, I've done it quite a bit.
まだだよね？まだ...うん。
Not yet? Still?
いや、でも、ま、これもし全部、あの虫あるのGTA
Yeah, but this is all from Mushiaru's GTA...
そうね、プーですかね？あの、ぜんぜんかいかな？
Zoo? Was it two times ago?
ぜんぜんかいだ。その時とめっちゃ喋った感あるけど。
Two times ago? We talked a lot back then, didn't we?
でも、実は1年、なんかんだ1年ちょっと、1年ちょっと？
Well, actually, for a year, well, somehow for a year or so... A year or so...
そうだよ。
Yeah.
その時にいまね、あの、あれ？
At that time, well, you know, um... Huh?
ん？
Hm?
あ、なんか
Oh, something...
あれ？
Huh?
なんか聞こえる？
Can you hear something?
なんですかこれ？これはなんですか？
What is this? What is this?
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
おめでとうございます！
やったー！
Yay!
みんなー！
Everyone!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
お疲れ様！かわいい！
Good job! Cute!
ありがと！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
みんな元気してんの！
Everyone's full of energy!
めちゃくちゃ多いな。多いな。
There are so many of them!
ということで、じゃあネオポリスのみんな、大集合です！
And with that, Neo-Porte everyone, we are all together!
やったー！
Yay!
じゃあ、自己紹介とさせていただけますか？
Can we do self-introductions, please?
そうですね。
Sure.
はい。
Yes.
お願いします。
Please go ahead.
じゃあ、エビオさんから。
Let's start with Ebio-san.
あ、はい、わかりました。
Ah, yes, understood.
こんぱんくす、ええ、ネオポリス1期生のXarebioです。ええ、よろしくお願いします。
Konpanx! I'm Xarebio from Neo-Porte's 1st Generation! Nice to meet you!
はーい、ありがとう！
Hi, thank you!
じゃあ次、ランちゃん！
Now next, Ran-chan!
あ、どうもこんばんは！日熊ランです。
Um, good evening! Hinokuma Ran here.
えー、何もしてん、ます！よろしくお願いします。
Um, I'm... not really doing anything special, but nice to meet you!
ええ、変わったね！
Eh, you're different!
じゃあ次、トトさん！
Okay, next, Totto-san!
はい、どこにも所属してないTedomixです。よろしくお願いします。
Hi, I'm Tedomix, affiliated with nowhere. Nice to meet you!
あるんですか、トトさんは？
Do you even have a affiliation, Totto-san?
どこにも所属していません。
I am affiliated with nowhere.
今年こそ？
This time?
今年こそはね？
This time for sure?
まあどっかに
Well, somewhere...
ホロライブでお待ちしてまーす。
I'm looking forward to it for hololive, you know.
一番違うやろ、それ！
That's totally different!
じゃあ次、マタちゃん！
Okay, next, Mata-chan!
はい、マザーです。よろしくお願いします。
Hi, Maza here. Nice to meet you!
えー、おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
唯一の実写、マジ。
The only one who's actually real.
ね、らしいね。
Right? It seems like it.
なんか、どうなってんだよTedomixさーん。
Wait, what are you doing, Tedomix?
恥ずかしいだろ、なんか逆に俺が。
It's embarrassing, you know, me being the opposite.
すいません、なんか、失礼します。
I'm sorry, excuse me.
ありがとね！
Thank you, ne!
次、コハクちゃん！
Next, Kohaku-chan!
はーい、コハク！Neo-Music's Phase 1所属の雫コハクです。やっほー！
Hi, Kohaku! Neo-Music's Phase 1 member, Shizuku Kohaku. Yahoo!
いぇーい！
Yay!
続いて、トモさん！
And next, Tomo-san!
はい、赤髪のとものです。え、おめでとうございまーす。
Hi, I'm Akagami no Tomo. Congratulations!
え、なんか硬いもん、さっきっていいのにこれ。
Wait, it's so hard to tell if someone's a VTR or not!
トモさんだけVTRじゃないよねこれ？いるよ、ほら。
Tomo-san, that wasn't a VTR, was it?
違う違う違う！
Different, different!
痛い痛い痛い！
It hurts! It hurts!
よかった、よかった。
Good, good.
いや、準備されてるかもしれない。
Yeah, you might be prepared.
トモさんも？
Tomo-san, too?
トモ...
Tomo...
はい、そしてねこたちー！
And finally, the cats!
こんばんは、XVsoねこどー。
Konban X-Vso, meow!
なんで？
Why?
え、XVsoなんて、X要素ないだろお前。
XVso? There's no X element there!
いや、言ってみたかった、言ってみたかった。
No, I wanted to try saying it, I wanted to try saying it!
いや、わかるよ、その気持ち。
I know, I know that feeling.
ねこどーなつ...
Neko-tachi is...
え、別に。
Eh, not really.
ヨクスではないから。
It's not Yox.
言いたくなる言葉Xということで。
So, using X for words you want to say—
みんな、ありがとう来てくれて。
Everyone, thank you for coming.
イエイ！イエイ！
Yay! Yay!
この間ね、あのハードコアのマイクらもやったりとか。
The other day, we also played Hardcore Minecraft.
ありましたね。ありましたね。
That's right, we did.
まあ、あれはね、全員生還できなかったけどな。
Well, not everyone made it back alive though.
無事にクリアしましたけどね、我々は。
We cleared it safely, though, us.
いやクリアすごい、マジで。
Clearing it is amazing, seriously.
凄かったよね。
It was amazing, right?
いや、ラスボス可能性よな、マジで。
Seriously, it was total final boss material.
マジか！マジか！マジボス可能性よな、マジで。
Seriously! Total boss material, seriously!
そうだよね、まださん。
That's right, Masa-san.
もう、ドキドキハラハラだったよね、あれ。
It was so thrilling and nerve-wracking, wasn't it?
大冒険だったわ。ねえ。
It was a grand adventure. Right?
そうそうそうそう、凄かったんだから。
Yeah, exactly, it was amazing.
今度二人でやるんでしょ？
You're doing it together next time, right?
タイマン、ハードコア。
One-on-one hardcore.
タイマンで。
One-on-one.
え、みんなに邪魔しに行こう。
Uh, let's go bother everyone.
あとはね、VCRのGTA3でもちょっとあったりとか。
And also, there was some stuff in VCR GTA3.
あったね。
There was.
ね、ずっとなんかあったね。
Right, there was stuff all along.
ワイルドネオポリスの集まりになると、欠席者がちょっといるらしいけど。
When Wild Neopolis gathers, it seems some people are absent.
いやね、マジでよかったわ。
Man, it was really great.
あれ、普通におつまんなかったっけ？
Wait, wasn't it normally fun?
え？あれ、何くんどうした？
Eh? Wait, what happened to Naru-kun?
え、どうした？え、どうしたんだっけ？
Eh, what happened? What happened again?
え、私最後までソロで。
Eh, I was solo until the very end.
映画出てさ、映画出てさ。
A movie came out, a movie came out.
しっかり声。
Clear voice.
あ、確かに！映画出でた、映画出でた。
Ah, true! A movie came out, a movie came out.
だから、私みたいに堂々としろ。
So, act as dignified as me.
自分では見られなかったっていう。
That I couldn't watch it myself.
アーカイブで、見に行ってください。
Please go check it in the archive.
ちょっとお時間がね、合わなくて。
Our times didn't quite match up.
まあまあ、そうですよね。
Well, yeah, that's right.
今度とかね、やってみたりとかしつつあるんですけど。
We were talking about maybe trying it next time, and stuff.
まあ、まだみんなでね、なんか今度はまた。
Well, we'll all get together again next time.
次こそは。
Next time for sure.
次こそはね。
今日3人でやっとしたし、呼んでくださいよ。
We finally did it with three people today, please invite us.
全員で歌うってこと？全員で歌おう。
Everyone singing together? Let's all sing together.
え、マジで10人で、10人で歌ってみよって話してるよ。
Eh, seriously, we're talking about trying to sing with 10 people.
歌ってみよって話してるよ。
Talking about trying to sing.
しようよ。しようよ。
Let's do it. Let's do it.
いや、てか今回ね、あの、やっぱアキローゼさんが言うから我々ね、まあ、ボクとレイドくんとか特にダンスもしたことない中が頑張って、エフも。
Well, this time, since Aki-rose-san said so, especially Boko and Rado-kun who have never danced before worked hard, and F too.
本当にめちゃ踊って、踊ったんだから。
Really danced a lot, danced so much.
めっちゃトビックス。
Super topics.
なんで踊ってないの？
Why didn't you dance?
から、言ったから、まあ、呼んでもらったら、そんなやりますが。
So, since you said so, if you invite us, we'll do it.
現地です、現地です。だよね、本当。
It's live, live. That's right, really.
ちょっとずつ増やしていこうじゃ、次はトトさん入れて、違う、違うじゃなくて、そっち側にオルから、次は。
Let's increase it little by little, next time with Toto-san—no, not like that, since they're on that side, next time.
そうだよね。おお！
That's right. Oh!
言ったね。言った、言った、言った。
You said it. Said it, said it.
大変だったよ。
It was tough.
そうだよ、うちら、めっちゃ頑張って踊ったんだよ。
That's right, we worked really hard and danced.
でもね、ダンス楽しかったっすよね、ほんとね。
But dancing was fun, wasn't it, really?
楽しかったね。
It was fun.
トトさんがやってるのめちゃおもろい。
Toto-san's part is super funny.
見たいね。めっちゃおもろいて言っちゃった。めちゃ見たい。
I want to see it. I ended up saying it's super funny. I really want to see it.
おもろい、めっちゃ見たい。キレキレのやつ見たい。
Funny, I really want to see it. I want to see crisp moves.
トトさんよ、やってくれよ。
Toto-san, please do it.
ましか、まあまあまあ、といったところで、お時間が迫ってるということで。
I see, well anyway, with that said, our time is running short.
はあ。早い。
Fast. It's fast.
10人もいるんだね。たくさん喋りたいと思うんですけども。
There are 10 people, so we want to talk a lot.
まあ、最後にもう1回みんなで、ボスをお祝いしようかと、いうことで。
Well, finally let's celebrate Boss all together one more time.
いいですか？
Is that okay?
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
じゃあ、せーの！
Then, ready, go!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
またやろうね。
Let's do it again.
やるぞ！おめでとう！
Let's do it! Congratulations!
おめでとう！バイバイ！バイバイ！
Congratulations! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
まるでお伽の話 終わり迎えた証
Like a fairy tale, proof of reaching the end
長過ぎる旅路から切り出した一節
A passage cut from a long journey
それはかつてこの地に 影を落とした悪を
It was the evil that once cast a shadow over this land
討ち取り勇者との短い旅の記憶
And the memory of a short journey with the hero
物語は終わり 勇者は眠りにつく
The story comes to an end, the hero falls into slumber
穏やかな日常をこの地に残して
Leaving behind a peaceful everyday life in this land
時の流れは無情に人を忘れさせる
The flow of time mercilessly makes people forget
そこに生きた軌跡も 錆び付いていく
Even the traces of life lived there begin to rust
それでも君の言葉も願いも勇気も
But even now, your words, wishes, and courage
今も確実に私の中で生きている
Are still vividly alive within me
同じ道を選んだ いつの間にかどうして
We chose the same path, but somehow, without realizing it,
頬を伝う涙の理由をもっと
I want to know more about the reason for the tears streaming down my cheeks
知りたいんだ 今更だって
Even at this late hour
共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば
If I trace our journey we walked together
まるで御伽の話 終わり迎えた証
Like a fairy tale, proof of reaching the end
長過ぎる旅路から切り出した一節
A passage cut out from a long journey
それはかつてこの地に 影を落とした悪を
It was the evil that once cast a shadow over this land
討ち取りし勇者との短い旅の記憶
and the memory of a short journey with the hero
物語は終わり 勇者は眠りにつく
The story ends, the hero falls into slumber,
穏やかな日常をこの地に残して
leaving behind a peaceful everyday life in this land.
時の流れは無情に 人を忘れさせる
The flow of time mercilessly makes people forget,
そこに生きた軌跡も 錆び付いていく
even the traces of life lived there begin to rust.
それなのに君の言葉も 願いも勇気も
But even now, your words, wishes, and courage
今も確かに私の中で生きている
are still vividly alive within me.
同じ道を選んだ いつの間にかどうして
We chose the same path, how, before we knew it,
頬を伝う涙の理由をもっと知りたいんだ
do I want to know more about the tears on my cheeks?
今更だって共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば
Even now, if I retrace the journey we walked together,
そこに君は居なくとも きっと見つけられる
I'm sure I'll find you even if you're not there.
あの旅を思い出せるように 残された目印
Markers left behind so I can recall that journey.
まるで御伽の話 終わり迎えた証
Like a fairy tale, proof of reaching the end,
私を変えた出会い 百分の1の旅路
encounters that changed me, one percent of a journey.
君の勇気をいつか 風がさらって
Someday, when the wind carries away your courage,
誰の記憶から消えてしまっても
and even if it disappears from everyone's memory,
私が未来に連れて行くから
I will take it with me into the future.
君の手を取った あの日全て始まった
I took your hand, and that day everything began.
思わずふっと笑ってしまうような
Even the trivial moments that make me smile
ありふれた時間が今も眩しい
are still radiant now.
知りたいんだ 今更だって
I want to know, even at this late hour,
振り返ればそこには いつでも優しく微笑みかける君がいるから
because whenever I look back, you are always there smiling gently.
新たな旅の始まりは 君が守り抜いたこの地に
The beginning of a new journey is in this land you protected,
芽吹いた命と共に
together with the sprouting life.
知りたいんだ 今更だって
I want to know, even at this late hour,
振り返ればそこには いつでも優しく微笑みかける
because whenever I look back, you are always smiling gently
君がいるから
because you exist.
新たな旅の始まりは 君が守り抜いたこの地に
The beginning of a new journey is in this land you protected,
芽吹いた命と きっと共に
together with the sprouting life.
あー見えてるみんなー！
Ah, can everyone see me?!
いや今日もね、いろんなゲストも来てくれたりお話しできたりしてめちゃくちゃ楽しいし、生誕ライブ最高！みんなありがとー！
Man, today various guests came and we talked, it's super fun, and the birthday live is the best! Thank you everyone!
あ、なんか聞こえる、聞こえる気がする...
Ah, I hear something... I feel like I hear something...
あ、誕生日！おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Ah, Happy Birthday! Congratulations! Congratulations!
え、それもう打ち合わせ済みそれ？
Eh, was that already coordinated?!
いや心はこもってるから。
Well, my heart is in it.
心こもってる？
Your heart is in it?
心込めていこって言ってた。
I said we'd put our hearts into it.
いやこの声はもしかして、Vさいのメンバー、プレデターと一緒のみんなー？
Wait, could this voice be... everyone from V-sai, together with Predator?
バレちまったか！
Found out!
バレバレだよ！
Dead giveaway!
ということでじゃあ、改めて自己紹介お願いします！じゃあディトちゃん！
With that, please introduce yourselves again! Now, Ditto-chan!
えーっと、はい、えっと、リジック所属のディとと申します。よろしくお願いします！
Um, yes, um, I'm Ditto from Rizic. Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
次、めいかちゃん！うたいめいかです。よろしくお願いします！
Next, Meika-chan! I'm Utai Meika. Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
そしてナッチさん！ナッチです。よろしくお願いします。緊張してる？
And Nacchi-san! I'm Nacchi. Nice to meet you. Are you nervous?
緊張しないね。こんなでかい舞台ね。そうだよね。
Not nervous. Such a big stage. That's right.
そして向井コーチ！はい、向井正紀です。おねがいしまーす！おめでとうございまーす！
And Coach Mukai! Yes, I'm Masaki Mukai. Please! Congratulations!
時間の許す限り話そう。いや、いいよいいよ。
Let's talk as long as time permits. Well, it's fine.
ま、このメンバーということで、プレデターと一緒のメンツ、今日は、あの、お声がけさせていただきまして、来ていただきました。ありがとね、みんな！
Well, with this members, the same gang as Predator, today I invited you all and you came. Thank you everyone!
こちらこそありがとうございます。呼んでいただいて。
Thank you for having us.
でもさ、こういうのってさ、もう何年も経ってもさ、全然緊張する。
But you know, even after all these years, I still get nervous.
ちっちゃいなー。ちっちゃいなー。
You're small. You're small.
でも我々といえば大会ありましたね。
But speaking of us, we had tournaments.
そうだよね、なんかでももう懐かしいというか、いつでもまだ経ってないけどね。大分経ってる。
That's right, it feels nostalgic, though it hasn't even been a year yet. It's been quite a while.
全然集まんねえじゃねえか、こいつら！
These guys never get together at all!
そうだよ！なんてこった。
That's right! Good grief.
で、なんで？
And why?
誕生日、逆に呼んでくれてありがとうね、本当にね。
Thanks for inviting me for your birthday instead.
そうだよ、ディトちゃんとはさ、ちょこちょこ同じチームになったりとか、イベント出たり、コラボしたりしてるんだけど。
That's right, with Ditto-chan, we've been on the same team, appeared at events, and collaborated.
あれでしょ、告白ちゃんってやつでしょ？
That's the confession thing, right?
あ、そうそうそうそう！俺見て、嫉妬込めるうつか悩んでやめたもん。
Ah, right right! I watched it and hesitated whether to put jealousy into it.
それはやってよ！
You're one to talk!
そういうのってやっぱね、可愛いってなるから、やってほしいよね。
That kind of stuff is cute, so I want you to do it.
いや、俺は可愛い売りしてねえから。
Hey, I'm not selling cute.
そっか、男気の方だ。
Right, you're the manly type.
男だからね、そうそうそう。
Because I'm a man, yeah, yeah.
そうだった。
That's right.
えでも、アキロゼがね、声かけなくても
But even if Aki doesn't call out to you,
ってても、遊んでくれたら嬉しいなと思うんだけど、
even if you didn't, I'd be happy if you played with me.
ナシだったらじゃあ、一緒に遊んでくれる？今後なんか一緒にね。
If it's a "no", will you play with me together in the future?
マリカ？
Mario Kart?
ああ、ああ。
Ah, I see.
いいね、マリカ？
Sounds good, Mario Kart?
マリカはね、ガチにするけど
Mario Kart, I'll play seriously, but
俺の庭やねん。
it's my turf.
みんなでできる。
Everyone can do it.
え？じゃあみかちゃんが強いんだ、じゃあ。
Eh? Then Mikachan is strong, then.
めっちゃ強いよ。
Super strong.
でもある、俺も一個もっと前の作品だけど、日本代表だったよ。
But you know, I was a Japanese representative in an older title.
え、やばい、強いの、いよいよじゃない？
Eh, seriously? Strong? Isn't that amazing?
え、めちゃ強いなの強発言超えられないじゃん、やばい。
Eh, I can't surpass that super-strong statement, oh no.
いや、やりますね。
Well, you'll do it.
本気で強い男は、そんな強いって言わわないんだ。
A truly strong man doesn't say he's strong like that.
うん。
Yeah.
日本代表って言われるとまずいか、ちょっと。
Saying you're a Japanese representative is a bit bad, maybe.
いやでも、カートの方は弱いです。バイクの方は強いですけど。
But well, kart is weak. Bike is strong though.
ああ、じゃあバイクは、あ、夏、あれか、バイク縛りで。
Ah, then bike is, ah, summer, is that it, bike-only.
いい！え、まじ、なんなんだ、すげえ。
Good! Eh, seriously, what is this, amazing.
え、すごいね、本当に。
Eh, that's amazing, really.
え、じゃあマリカコラボ、やるか？
Eh, then shall we do a Mario Kart collab?
やったっていい。
It's fine if we do.
やったっていい、じゃあ今後もね、
It's fine if we do, so in the future too,
ぜひ、あの、遊んでもらえたら嬉しいなって思ってるんで、アキロゼからこう、声をかけたら、みんなからもぜひね、気軽にこのコラボも遊んで声かけてくださいね。
please, um, I'd be happy if you'd play with me, so if Aki calls out to you, please feel free to play and invite us for collabs too.
もちろんナッチさんからも、そうだよ。
Of course, from Nacchi-san too, that's right.
最近なんか絶対しない。
Recently, like, absolutely won't.
絶対しない、ひどい。
Absolutely won't, how awful.
絶対しねえよ、アークだっていいのに。
Absolutely won't, even though Ark is fine.
じゃ、アークやりましょうよ。アークやりたいね。
Then let's play Ark. I want to play Ark.
アークやりたい。
I want to play Ark.
そうだよ、アークやりたいの。
That's right, I want to play Ark.
アークやるか？うん。
Shall we play Ark? Yeah.
あれも普通に好きなんだよね。
I normally like that too.
あ、本当?じゃあどうっすか?
Ah, really? Then how about it?
いや、やれる人が増えて嬉しい。アーク友達、好きなんだから、アーク友達にもなれるということで、じゃあ今後も色々やりましょう。
Yeah, I'm glad more people can play. Ark friends, since I like it, we can become Ark friends too, so let's do various things in the future.
やりましょう。
Let's do it.
はい、じゃあ今日は忙しいところ来てくれてありがとうございますね。
Yes, thank you for coming despite being busy today.
じゃあ次は、ありがとうございます。
Then next, thank you very much.
絶対優勝しようね。絶対優勝しような。
Let's definitely win. Let's definitely win.
マジで？
Seriously?
優勝しよう、絶対ね、だって、私達一取ったから、俺達、そうだよ、それを誇って生きてんだから、優勝してやるわ、トロフィー。
Let's win, definitely, because we took 1st place, we're proud of that and live by it, so we'll win the trophy.
はい、じゃあまたね、またね、バイバーイ、バイバーイ。
Yes, then see you again, see you again, bye-bye, bye-bye.
燃えるアヴァンチュール
Burning adventure
密会のピアール
Secret meeting appeal
溶けていくルール
Melting rules
純情を装ってる泥棒猫の罠は誘い
Disguised as purity, the stray cat's trap is an invitation
bam bam we're damned
誰もうけつけないなら「正解」と同じでしょ
If no one accepts it, it's the same as the correct answer
bam bam we're slammed
甘い甘い捕食的な愛　そんな「駆け引き」かなうわけない
Sweet, sweet predatory love, no way such bargaining can work
私欲のまま狩るだけだから
Because I just hunt according to my desires
二人しか知らないこのロマンス　罪な味で染めるこのパラダイス
This romance only the two of us know, this paradise dyed in a sinful taste
麻痺する前にもう点火して求めよ
Ignite it before you get paralyzed, and beg for it
危険なヒアソビを
Dangerous playing with fire
甘えて悶えて肌に牙を向いて
Act spoiled, writhe, bare your fangs at my skin
今宵限りのファンタジア　待ってないでさあ踊って
A fantasia for tonight only, don't wait around, come on and dance
その指焦がしてる dissatisfaction
Dissatisfaction, burning your fingers
あとはなすがあまま　転げ落ちるままさ
Just let it be, rolling down
地獄の底まで down low, low, low, oh
To the bottom of hell, down low, low, low, oh
罪の意識さえ一口で飲み込んで
Even a sense of guilt, swallow it in one gulp
こぼれてる吐息が　止まらない刺激が
The overflowing sighs, the unceasing stimuli
人のものだろうが　ただ掠め取るだけ
Even if it belongs to someone else, I'll just snatch it away
燃えるアヴァンチュール
Burning adventure
密会のピアール
Secret meeting appeal
溶けていくルール
Melting rules
いたずらまごことそんな言葉じゃずっとぬるい
Mischief, playing house, words like that are way too mild
bam bam we're damned
一瞬の儚い夢こそグサって残るでしょ
An ephemeral dream for just a moment leaves a stab, right?
bam bam we're slammed
あなたとわたしで何がしたい？　そんな「計算」だってあてにしない
What do you want to do with me and you? I don't rely on such calculations
熱と嘘で答えかぎえるから
Because the answer is washed away by heat and lies
後ろ手で鍵をかけてランデブー　優しく獲物を狙ってほくそ笑む
Lock the door behind us and rendezvous, smiling slyly while aiming for gentle prey
喰らいついたならもう点火して　交差してよ
Once you bite into it, ignite it, cross over
身に浸くヒアソビを
Ugly playing with fire
モラルも理性も置き去りの獣に
To the beast that leaves morals and reason behind
絡め取って 楽にして ここから先を染めていこう ファッション
Catch me, ease me, and dye everything beyond here—fashion!
愛のことばなんて もういらないから 本当 この羽も
I don't need words of love anymore, truly, even these wings—
Down Low Low Low Low ワガママ口に出して 魂試される Heart
Down, low, low, low, low, speak your selfishness, a heart whose soul is tested.
愛は知恵の No return 虜に染めろカラー もう戻れないなら
Love is wisdom's no return; dye me captive in color. If there's no turning back,
さあ ぶち抜ける影
come on, pierce through the shadows!
さあ 伏せていて ウイスキーの香りの口づけで
Now, keep your eyes down with a kiss scented like whiskey...
今宵は竜胆と戯れの 仕留めて火をつけて 尖らせてよ
Tonight, with a play of gentians, capture it, set a fire, and sharpen it.
とがらせてよ まだ掛けたヒヤソビを
Sharpen it, the dangerous play we still cast.
孤独が 鼓動が ここじゃやめられないじゃん
Loneliness, heartbeats—you just can't stop them here, right?
背徳感のトラジディ 誰かさんとの約束ごと ただ奪い去るだけ
A tragedy of taboo, a promise with someone else—just snatching it away.
求めてよ 危険なヒヤソビを 甘えて もたれて 帰り道を忘れても
Demand it, a dangerous hiyasobi. Even if you act spoiled, lean on it, and forget the way home,
今夜限りのファンタジア 待てないで さあ踊って
a one-night-only fantasia. Don't wait, come on, dance!
その指殺して見せた ファッション あとはのぞむまま
A fashion that showed murder in those fingers; the rest is just as you wish.
焦げ付くままさ 地獄の底まで
Leaving it charred, all the way to the depths of hell.
Down Low Low Low Low
痺れる意識さえ 爪を食い込んで こぼれてる時が
Even numbed consciousness, sinking claws in, the moments spilling over—
止まない刺激が 人のものだろうが
unending stimuli, even if it belongs to someone else—
どこまで盗るだけ 危険な夜中
just stealing all the way to a dangerous midnight.
紅蓮のビューティ 蜜会のミステール 溶けていくルルル
Crimson beauty, the mystère of secret rendezvous, melting away, lulu-lu...
いぇーい！いぇーい！ということで、チークマロのめんでしたー！
Yay! Yay! And that was Team Maro's members!
いやなんか…嬉しい！ここに来てくれての、本当嬉しいなー！
Man, I'm so happy! I'm genuinely so glad you all came here!
いや本当ありがとうございます、こんな、大きなライブに呼んでいただいて…
Seriously, thank you so much for inviting me to such a huge live show...
マジでヒロインなんで！すっげえ！ねえ！マジで！マジでひろ…
We're seriously the heroines! It's amazing! Right? Seriously! Seriously, heine—
いやでも…や、今日はね、アキロゼの生誕祭にわざわざ来てくれても…
Well, but... you know, thank you so much for coming all the way to Aki-rose's birthday celebration...
お誕生日おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Congratulations! Congratulations!
ありがと！いつかね、やってみたかったことだからね、一つ願いが叶ったのも当然なんだけどね。
Thank you! It's something I've wanted to do someday, so naturally, one of my wishes came true.
てことで、じゃあ、せっかくなんできこ、自己紹介、しときますかね？
So, since we have the chance, shall we go ahead and do self-introductions?
はい！いぇーい！つよい！はい！
Yes! Yay! Strong! Yes!
じゃあ、ヒマちゃんからお願いしまーす！ はーい！皆さんどうも、おはひまおはひまおはひま、たむりひまわりがちゃおんぷいとんほんまひまわりです！
Then Hima-chan, please go ahead! Hi everyone, hello Hima-hello Hima-hello Hima, Tamuri Himawari is here, chao onpuiton honma Himawari!
本物だー！ちゃんと言ったよ！口も回らん！めちゃ元気！え、感動した、なんか！
She's the real deal! She said it properly! My tongue is tripping! So energetic! I'm so touched, somehow!
え、いいの？ほんものだーって言った、いや。まあこっちからしても本物だって感じだけどね。
Wait, is that okay? You said she's the real deal, huh. Well, from our perspective, you're the real deal too.
じゃあ続いてべにちゃんお願いします！ はい皆さん、えー、おはセクシー、こんセクシー。あ、どうもVspoのセクシー担当、夜乃べにです。どうも、こんにちわ。
Next up, Beni-chan please! Hi everyone, uh, good morning sexy, hello sexy. Ah, hello, I'm Vspo's sexy representative, Yano Beni. Hello, good afternoon.
いろせき！いろせきだって！今、え、今作りました！
Iro-sexy! Iro-sexy she says! Just now, uh, she just made that up!
いやそんな挨拶いらないぐらいこれセクシーだけどね。今作りました。はい、おはセクシー。
Well, this is so sexy you don't even need a greeting like that. I just made it up. Yes, good morning sexy.
いやちょっと、このメンツの前では、ひまちゃんの目の前でしか言えないこれ。ちょっとあ、ちょっとちょこ先生の前ではちょっとコンセクシーなんて言えない。
Wait a second, in front of this lineup, I can only say this in front of Himawari. Wait, ah, in front of Choco-sensei, I can't say something like 'con-sexy'.
ひまだってセクシー担当でやってるんだから！いやいやうそ嘘嘘！
Himawari is doing her best as the sexy rep too! No, no, no, lies, lies, lies!
どこの大がセクシー担当なんだよ！
Which university is your sexy rep from?!
いやいや、じゃあ、ほろのね、セクシー担当にもお願いしますか。じゃあチョコ先生お願いします！
Well well, then, let's ask Holo's sexy rep as well. Choco-sensei, please!
えへ、じゃあ言っちゃおっかなー。えと、変わる？
Hehe, then shall I say it? Uh, switch?
ちょこん… ホロライブセクシー担当、癒月ちょこでーす。
Chokon... HoloLive's sexy representative, Yuzuki Choco here.
え、待って、なに？え、待って、なんなんだ？え、待って待って、ちょこ先生、何をちょこまったの？
Wait, what? Wait, what is this? Wait, wait, Choco-sensei, what did you choke on?
え、それは、それはもうご想像にお任せします。お願いします。え、待って、時の流れが今五倍ぐらいゆっくりしてて。
Uh, as for that, I'll leave that to your imagination. Please. Uh, wait, the passage of time right now feels about five times slower.
さあ日向ちゃん、これがセクシー担当だ。
Now, Hinata-chan, this is the sexy department!
なるほどね。
I see!
周りです。
Around and around!
なんか違うんだよなあ。
That's kind of different, though.
いいねえ。
Nice!
いやでもさ、なんかみんなね、このちくまろのさ、よにんはさ、まあセクシー担当って、まあ前のAPEXかな、なんかのコラボの時に言ってたからね。
But you know, since all four of us Chikumaro members were designated as the "sexy department" during some past collaboration like APEX...
今日はセクシーな曲を4人でやってみたいなと思って、この曲にしたの。
I thought I'd want us four to perform a sexy song today, so I chose this one.
なるほどね。
I see!
確かに！
Totally!
確かにめっちゃセクシー。
Yeah, super sexy!
いやダンスがね、めっちゃセクシーだったと思わないですか？めっちゃセクシーだったでしょ？
Don't you think the dance was super sexy? It was super sexy, right?
ね、めっちゃびっくりした。
Right? I was so surprised!
振り付け見た時、「これいけるかな」と思ったけど。
When I saw the choreography, I thought, "Can we really pull this off?"
いや、めっちゃよかった。
Man, it was so good.
いやちょこもいつもの以上に腰くねくねさせちゃった。くねくね！それましたね、だいぶ。
Choco-sensei even twisted her hips more than usual. Twisting! We really went all out with that.
日向ちゃんもセクシーに磨きがかかって。
Hinata-chan's sexiness has been polished up too!
いや本当だよ！セクシーすぎてやばい。
Seriously! It's too sexy, it's dangerous.
日向ちゃんもね、セクシーすぎて爆発しちゃうかもしれないから。
Hinata-chan might just explode from being too sexy.
だっせ？
Really?
爆発するところをぜひ見せてもらえたらなと思うんですけど、まあ今年も、ちくまろの4人で色々楽しいこととか、まあセクシーなこととか、できたら嬉しいなと思ってるんで。
I'd love to see where you explode, but anyway, I hope the four of us Chikumaro members can do lots of fun things and sexy things together this year!
そんなこと？いや、それはちょっと言えない。
Things like that? Well, I can't really say.
それ言うとなんか、もっと日向はこう言われちゃう。
If I say that, people will say even more things about Hinata!
じゃあ、ローションズもしましょう。ローションズ！やべえやべえ。
Then let's do Lotions too! Lotions! Oh crap, oh crap!
この2時3時さんお迎えしまして、リスナーさんお願いします。もう使います。
Welcoming the guests, listeners please! We'll use it now.
ということで日向ちゃん、ベニーちゃん、ちょこせん、ありがとね！ありがとう！お疲れ様でした！
And with that, Hinata-chan, Benny-chan, Choco-sen, thank you so much! Thank you! Great job everyone!
いやあ、今日の誕生日はめちゃくちゃすごいだ！こんなにね、いろんなゲストの人たちが来てくれて、たくさんお話したり、歌ったり踊ったりして楽しかったあ。
Man, today's birthday is incredible! So many guests came by, we talked a lot, sang, and danced—it was so much fun!
アキロゼさん。
Aki-rose-san.
お？お？もしかしてその声は？
Oh? Oh? Could that voice be...?
樋口！樋口！
Higuchi! Higuchi!
おお、村長！
Oh, Village Chief!
村長だー！
It's the Village Chief!
アキロゼさん、おめでとうございます！
Aki Rosenthal-san, congratulations!
ありがとう村長！え、来てくれたの？村長1人で来てくれたの、もしかして？
Thank you, Village Chief! Wait, you came? Did you come all by yourself, Village Chief?
いやいやいや、まさか！みんないますよ。
No no no, no way! Everyone's here!
もしかして？
Could it be?
おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations!
え、ガエル村のみんなだ！わざわざみんな来てくれたんだ！
Eh, everyone from Gaeru Village! You all came all this way!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
二度目ましてしてもいいよね。
It's okay even if it's our second time, right?
二度目まして。
Nice to meet you again.
また来ちゃった。また来てくれたの？待ってた待ってた！また来てくれたのもあるんだね。
You came back again. You came back? I was waiting! Some people came back again.
とことんでね、本日のガエル村のみんなが来てくれました！
So today, everyone from Gaeru Village came to join us!
ということでじゃあ、おめでとう！おめでとう！
And with that, congratulations! Congratulations!
せっかくなんでね、自己紹介タイムさせてもらいましょうかね。
Since we have the chance, let's do a self-introduction time!
え、マジかよ！
Eh, seriously?!
いや気合入れてあとお願いしますね。
Put your spirit into it, please!
じゃあ、なんかアキロゼのね、パーカー来てくれてる村長！わあ、ありがとう！自己紹介お願いします。
Now, Village Chief, who's wearing Aki-rose's hoodie! Wow, thank you! Please introduce yourself.
自己紹介します。え、来春ソルクモット所属の樋口です。
I'll introduce myself. Um, I'm Higuchi from Spring Solkumott.
あの、普段ね、まあ薬と入った練習して、アキロゼさんのガイルをあの、鍛えてる村長と呼ばれるものです。よろしくお願いします。
Uh, usually I practice with medicine and stuff, and I'm the Village Chief who trains Aki Rosenthal's Gaill. Nice to meet you!
丁寧な！
So polite!
よう、村長！村長！村長！
Hey, Village Chief! Village Chief! Village Chief!
続いてドンさん！
Next up, Don-san!
えー、3人グループで活動しております。3人ショのドンピシャと申します。
Uh, I operate in a 3-person group. I'm Donpisha from Shanninsho.
えー、ガイル村では副村長と呼ばれておりまして、アキさんのコーチなんぞもしておりますね。
Um, in Gaeru Village, I'm called the Vice Village Chief, and I also coach Aki-san and stuff.
いつもありがとう！
Thank you as always!
よしよしよし！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations! Congratulations!
いや、続いてどうしようかな。リモニ先生？
Now, what should we do next? Rimony-sensei?
俺？
Me?
そこでね、準備してなかったな。
I wasn't prepared for this just now.
えーっと、そっすね。結構アキロゼさんと最近色々お話しさせていただいたりして、チーム友達でもね。
Um, let's see. Lately I've been talking a lot with Aki Rosenthal-san, and we're even team friends.
そうすね。あの、ちょっとガイルじゃちょっとアキ最近使ってない確か。
That's right. Uh, lately Aki hasn't been using Gaill much in Gaeru, right?
いや、まあまあまあ、でも一応タマも、まあ、タマもね、ガイルもタマも。
Well, well, well, but at least Tama also... Tama too, Gaill and Tama both.
え、なんですか？
Eh, what is this?
なんかそこ避けてくれないの？
Won't you step aside there?
そうね、じゃあリモネス先生とおもいます。よろしくお願いします。
Right. Well, let's start with Rimones-sensei. Nice to meet you.
はーい、リモネス
Hi, Rimones here!
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you!
じゃあ続いて、数よ？はい。
Next up is Kazuyo? Yes.
あ、2期生所属の玉餅数よです。
Ah, I'm Kazuyo Tamamochi from the 2nd generation.
いや、アキロゼさんとはあの、同じモダンガイルズ会だったということで。
Apparently, Aki Rosenthal-in and I were in the same Modangirls club.
そう、そう、そう。
That's right, that's right!
あの、そうですよね。あの、モダンガイルの辛いところを唯一共有できる仲間だと思うと
I felt you were the only comrade with whom I could share the struggles of being a modangirl...
いや、そうなんだよね。すごい、心強かったんだよね。
Yeah, exactly. It was so reassuring.
辛い部分なんだよね。ジタバタしてる。
The tough parts, you know. Floundering around.
共感力ってやっぱ大事だからね。うん、うん、うん。
Empathy is really important, after all. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much!
はい。はーい。
Yes. Hi!
じゃあ続いて、Linge？はい、ガイル村所属JPスカイVスポキタギ連です。よろしくお願いします。
Next up, Linge? Yes, I'm Linge, a JP Sky V-Spo kitagiren belonging to Gail Village. Nice to meet you!
誕生日おめでとう、アキロゼさん！
Happy birthday, Aki Rosenthal!
と、Lingeとまださ、ちゃんとさ、ゆっくりコラボできてない気がするんだよね。
Linge and I still haven't really had a proper, relaxing collab yet, I feel.
え、そうだよね。なんかさ、もう雑談コラボとかいっそやろうみたいな話したよね、こないだ。
Eh, right? We even talked about doing a chatting collab outright the other day, didn't we?
あ、した、した、した！
Ah, we did, we did, we did!
あれだよね。
That's right, isn't it?
そう、やっぱ、あれだよね、多分電流デスマッチの時だけ？
Right, was it only during the electric shock death match?
あ、そうかも！あ、その時だけなんだ。
Ah, maybe! Ah, only that time.
なんかね、ちゃんと組んだのはその時ぐらいかも、割と。
I guess that was pretty much the only time we really teamed up.
そうだよね。で、今年はやろう、絶対に。やろう。
That's right. So this year, let's do it, definitely. Let's do it!
確かに。
True.
絆はできて、結託はしてたね。結託はしてた。
A bond was formed, we were in cahoots. We were in cahoots!
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you!
また電流、いやまた電流流されちゃうわ、守り守りますやんか、そんな。
We'll get electrocuted again. We'll protect each other, right?
頑張って守りますやんか。じゃあそして、2度めましての猫たちー！
I'll do my best to protect you! And now, for the second time meeting, the cats!
さきぶりです。猫塚なで。
Long time no see. Nademachi Neko.
あ、じゃあさっき話したね。そうね、さっき話したけど。
Ah, well, we talked earlier. That's right, we talked earlier, but.
さっきはApexをよくやってます。
Earlier, I said I play Apex a lot.
あ、やってるんだ。
Oh, you play it?
一緒にさ、教えてほしいゲーム。
I want you to teach me a game together.
いいよ、全然！やろう。上手いもんな、上手いよ、そうだよ。
Sure, absolutely! Let's do it. You're good, right, you're good.
ということで、いっぱいいっぱい教えてもらう配信をしたいと思うんだけど。
So I'd like to do a stream where you teach me lots of things, but...
以上、ガイル村のメンバーで
That's all for the Gail Village members...
おい、以上じゃない！びっくりした。
Hey, don't say 'that's all'! I was startled.
なんて自己紹介しようか必死に考えてたからさ。
Because I was desperately thinking about how to introduce myself.
じゃあ裏切り者の犬小屋ー！あ、ラニスターさん。
Now, the traitor's doghouse! Ah, Lanistar-san.
いやいやいや、そんな、アキロゼさんをガイル村に連れてきた男、ホロスターズ所属アルランディスです。
No, no, no, I'm Aruran-desu from Holostars, the man who brought Aki Rosenthal to Gail Village.
今日はよろしくお願いいたします。
Looking forward to working with you today!
いや、そうなんだよね。実はね、こう何人か引き連れてるの。
Yeah, exactly. Actually, you've been leading a bunch of people.
いや、ソニソニサイモンじゃないの、平気？
Wait, isn't it SoniSoni Simon? Are you okay?
ソニソニサイモンはほら、あの、ガイルに困ってる人のところに寄せるだから。全然俺は知らない、あの人のことは全然俺じゃない。
SoniSoni Simon, you see, gathers people who are in trouble with Gail. I don't know that person at all, it's not me.
あの妖精、ちょっとタッチ悪いけどね。
That fairy has a bit of a bad touch, though.
でもある意味、アキさん本当に公園で彷徨ってるところを村にね。
But in a sense, you wandered around the park, Aki-san, and came to the village.
公園で彷徨ってたんだ。
You were wandering in the park!
危ない感じの彷徨い方。
Wandering in a dangerous kind of way.
彷徨ってたら迎えに来たんだよね。
While wandering around, you came to pick me up.
そう、こんな、こんなとこにいるんじゃないよって。どんな、どんな立場なんだお前！
Yeah. 'You shouldn't be in a place like this!' What kind of position are you taking, you punk!
でもこんな扱いしてるけど、実質ガイル村に引き連れてきてくれた恩人ということでね。
But even though you treat me like this, you're essentially the benefactor who brought me to Gail Village.
あら、素晴らしい！
Oh, wonderful!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ガイル村も、あれ、先月か。えっと、eスポーツアワード流行語大賞2024も受賞したし。
Gail Village also won the eSports Award Buzzword Grand Prix 2024 last month, right?
いや、そう、そう、そうだよ。
Yeah, that's right, exactly.
すごいよ、まじで。
It's amazing, seriously.
だってそんなグローバルだったんだ。びっくりしちゃった。
I mean, it was that global! I was so surprised.
びっくりしたよね。
Surprised, right?
だから今年もね、ガイル村でなんか色々、なんか遊んだりとかも。
So this year too, in Gail Village, playing various things, etc.
そうだね、一緒にできたらいいよね。
That's right, it would be nice if we could do it together.
なんかだってアキさんなんかもこのゲームやろうよみたいな言ってたっけね。
I mean, Aki-san, you were saying 'Let's play this game,' weren't you?
そう。
Yes.
あ、そう、そうだよ。
Ah, right, right.
でもなんか新年会呼ばれない。これ。
But somehow I wasn't invited to the New Year's party. This.
ということで、ありがとうございました！本日は。
With that, thank you very much for today!
じゃあ今日はありがとうー！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Well then, thank you today! Happy birthday!
ようこそお越しなさったご主人様
Welcome, master of the house,
隣に座らせーの
Come sit right beside me—
萌え萌え萌え萌え
Moe moe moe moe!
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who even enjoys something like this?
ねえ教えて笑顔で up, pull, pull
Tell me, with a smile: up, pull, pull!
愛そうを忘れてご苦労様
Forget all the pleasantries, good work today,
ようこそお越しなさった ご主人様
Welcome, master, who has come all this way,
隣に座って せーのっ
sit next to me, ready, go!
燃え 燃え 燃え 燃え
Moe, moe, moe, moe!
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who's going to be happy with something like this?
ねえ教えて 笑顔で up pull pull
Hey, tell me with a smile, up pull pull!
愛想を忘れてご苦労様
Thanks for your hard work dropping the charm,
私とあなたで せーのっ
you and me, ready, go!
luv luv luv luv
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who's going to be happy with something like this?
ねえ教えて 笑顔で up pull pull
Hey, tell me with a smile, up pull pull!
ひらり はらり 女の子
Gracefully, flutteringly, a girl,
ふわり ふわり 言の葉のsaw
softly, gently, a saw of words.
それってつまりおさめなこ 感情的リアル 笑顔で up pull pull
That means a cold girl—emotionally real, with a smile, up pull pull!
人は見かけによらぬもの
You can't judge a book by its cover,
嘘を嘘だと見抜けない
you can't see through lies as lies.
奇々怪々そでその革
Bizarre, mysterious, sleeves and leathers,
鳥肌 鮹肌
goosebumps, octopus skin!
un deux trois
間違ったご指名をお伺いします
We await your mistaken nominations,
私とあなたで せーのっ
you and me, ready, go!
luv luv luv luv
これは何処派手にご苦労様
Thanks for your flashy hard work here,
遊びましょう 笑顔で up brrrt brrrt
let's play with a smile, up brrrt brrrt!
ひらり はらり ここは何処
Gracefully, flutteringly, where is this place?
ふわり ふわり 掃討 let me show
Softly, gently, sweeping, let me show!
それってつまりおさめなこ 確証的リアル
That means a cold girl—conclusive reality,
笑顔で up brrrt brrrt
with a smile, up brrrt brrrt!
歌い出す 秘密の鐘
The secret bell starts to ring,
終わる事のない この世界
in this world that never ends.
悲しい子供は
Sad children,
虚しい子供は
empty children,
眠らせて お飯事
let them sleep, playing house.
おままごと 遊びましょう
Let's play house and have some fun,
笑顔で up pull pull
with a smile, up pull pull!
ひらり はらり 女の子
Gracefully, flutteringly, a girl,
ふわり ふわり 言の葉のsaw
softly, gently, a saw of words.
それってつまりおさめなこ 感情的リアル
That means a cold girl—emotionally real,
笑顔で up pull pull
with a smile, up pull pull!
遊びましょう 笑顔で up pull pull
Let's play with a smile, up pull pull!
up pull pull
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
どうも、ようこそ！
Welcome, everyone!
はい、いらっしゃいませ！どうもはじめまして！
Welcome! Nice to meet you!
はじめまして…いやちょっと…
Nice to meet you... wait, hold on...
なんかあんまり距離を置いちゃいけないかなと思ってさ
I felt like we shouldn't keep too much distance.
ということでね、えー「モエチャッカファイア」歌ってみたチャンネルで…
So, uh, on the "Moechakkafire" cover channel...
はい、「モエチャッカ」した！
Yes, we "Moechakka"-ed!
「モエチャッカ」ランディスです！
I'm "Moechakka" Landis!
「モエチャッカ」オーガです！
And I'm "Moechakka" Oga!
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you!
来てくれて！
Thanks for coming!
いやいやいや、もう呼ばれたらば、もう呼ばれたらどこでも行きますよ。
No, no, if we're called, we'll go anywhere!
パッと出てきてパッと帰りますんでね、はい。
We'll pop in and pop right back out, yeah.
仕事人だなそれは。
That's pure professionalism.
え、ところでアキロゼさんって…あれですよね、エルフと…あ、精霊…精霊の…はい。
By the way, Aki-rose... you're an elf and... oh, spirits...
よしよしよしよし。
Right, right, right.
あの、今ってちょっとその、センシティブかもしれないけど、なんかだいぶ距離感測りすぎじゃない？
Um, maybe this is a sensitive topic right now, but aren't we measuring our distance a bit too much?
え、確かに。どういう…そんなレディに、ねえ？年齢回しとか。
Oh, true. What do you mean... asking a lady her age and stuff?
ええと、年齢数えられるの？はい、数えられる。
Uh, can you count your age? Yes, I can.
デビューが200歳と＋17で、217歳！
Debut was 200 years old plus 17, so 217 years old!
で、アキロゼさんは1年に1歳歳をとって、みんなと同じ時間を生きてるんで…つまり、7回目の誕生日だから…24…あや、224歳！
And Aki-rose ages one year every year, living in the same time as everyone... meaning, since it's her 7th birthday... 24... wait, 224 years old!
おおおお！おめでとうございます！
Whoa! Congratulations!
まだまだ若造だな。2で割れます。
Still a youngster. We can divide that by 2.
素晴らしい！まだまだ若造だな。
Wonderful! Still just a youngster.
あ、そっか、そうか。魔人だから長いいんだ。
Ah, right. Since you're a majin, you live long.
そっか、何歳なの？
Right, how old are you?
5,000… 5,035歳。
5,000... 5,035 years old.
やばい！超先輩だった。えぐいな！
Whoa! Total seniors. That's intense!
そりゃその貫禄出るわ。
No wonder you have that presence.
エルフなると？ いや、俺20代でやってるから。20代だから。
What about an elf? Well, I'm doing it in my 20s. I'm in my 20s.
お前何歳だおい！20代だから。
How old are you, hey! I'm in my 20s.
ここ多分、平均取ったらイカついことになるぞ、多分。
If we take the average here, it's going to be intense.
平均何歳？3,000歳とか？3,000、そうなる。
Average age? Like 3,000? 3,000, yeah.
2,500ちょっととかになる？ 俺のせいじゃんそれ！
Like around 2,500? That's my fault!
だいぶオーガに引っ張られることになるかもしれない。
We might be dragged way up by the Oga.
でもね、今回は、この3人でね、この「モエチャッカ」を歌ってみたいって言って…
But you know, this time, the three of us wanted to sing "Moechakka"...
そうそうそうそうそうそう。
That's right, exactly.
そうなの。で、オーガにね、やっぱね、低音ボイスがこの曲は絶対ね、合うんじゃないかと。
That's right. And Oga's low voice would definitely fit this song, right?
でもむずかしかったよ。
But it was difficult.
難しかった！頑張ってくれてさ。ダンスも難しかった実わ。
It was difficult! But you worked hard. The dancing was also tough actually.
ああ、確かにね！ダンス、なんかでもね、よかった、踊れたし。この曲ね、よく聞いてたから俺。
Ah, true! The dance... well, it was good, we danced. Because I listened to this song a lot.
踊れたの嬉しかった！なかなかね、そのメイドさんのね、キャラクターの歌だから…
I was so glad we could dance! So, since it's a maid's character song...
ね、男1人じゃ歌わないから
You know, since we don't sing alone as guys...
こうやって呼んでもらわないと歌えないような曲だった
It was a song we couldn't sing unless invited like this.
やっぱ我々基本男の時って男だけで歌うから
Well, usually when it's just guys, we only sing with guys.
そうだね
That's right.
ちょっと珍しい感じがして楽しかったですね
It felt a little unusual and was really fun.
あ、よかった、よかった
Oh, I'm glad, I'm glad.
ありがとうございました本当にね
Thank you very much, truly.
なんかこういう形でやるのアキローゼも初めてだから
Doing it in this format is a first for Aki Rosenthal too,
あ、そうなんだ
Oh, is that right?
そう
Yeah.
じゃあなんかそんなチャレンジな日に呼んでもらったみたいな感じなんですか
So it's like you invited me on such a challenging day?
そう、で3人にね、結構共通点があって
Yeah, and the three of us have quite a few things in common.
お
Oh?
なんと3人、えーえーえーえーお！
Surprisingly, the three of us... A-A-A-A-oh!
確かに、みんなね、赤から赤髪アキロゼ
True, everyone... from red, red hair, Aki Rosenthal,
アルランディス
Arurandeisu,
おー！
Oh!
さらに
And further,
さらに？え、まだあるの？
Further? Eh, there's more?
イメージカラーは、え？
The image color is... eh?
グリーンですよ
Green!
あ、私もグリーンで、アキロゼもグリーン
Ah, I'm green too, and Aki Rosenthal is green.
あ、全員緑なんだ！
Ah, everyone's green!
全員緑だ、あ、確かに
Everyone's green, oh, true.
今証明もね、あ、そっか確かにね
Even the lighting right now... ah, right, true.
緑になってるから
Since it's turned green,
ね、みんないいでしょ？自然に馴染んでるでしょ
Right, isn't it nice? It blends in naturally.
確かに
True.
そうなんです。実は何でその3人でね考えてたんだ
That's right. Actually, I was wondering why those three...
あー！
Ah!
あ、そっかそんな共通点あったんだ俺
Ah, right, I had that kind of common point.
ちゃんと考えててたんだ、安心したおい
You actually thought about it, I'm relieved, hey.
うわー考えてなさそうに見えてるって話
Whoa, talking about looking like you didn't think about it.
そんなこと、そんなこと
No way, no way.
もう一回燃やしに行く？
Going to burn it again?
恐ろしい恐ろしい恐ろしい、どんどん燃やしに行ってください
Scary, scary, go ahead and burn it more.
歓迎なんだ
It's a welcome.
本当にありがとうございました、なんか
Thank you really very much, like,
めったにない機会だったから
it was a rare opportunity,
いやそうだよ、初めてだよだって、男性にして、僕たちも楽しかったし。
Yeah, that's right, it's the first time with male guests!
まだ、ある！
There's still more!
よし！
Alright!
じゃあちょっとこれからも頑張ってください
Well, please keep doing your best from now on.
もっと燃やしてください。いや本当に、じゃあ本当に、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Burn it more. Then really, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございますね！
Thank you! Thank you!
お疲れ様でした！また！また、ええ、左右に分かれてバイバーイ！
Good job! See you, parting left and right, bye-bye!
見えないところで合流するから。新しいな
We'll merge where we can't be seen. That's new.
熱くなった銀のメタリックハート
My silver, metallic heart heated up
導火線に火をつけてあげる
I'll light the fuse!
不思議なほどハイな気分さ
I feel so high it's strange.
砂塵を巻き上げて行こう
Let's kick some dust and go!
悲鳴をまじえ暴走する鼓動
A wild pulse coupled with the shouts,
目の前にはミサイルの雨
before my eyes a rain of missiles.
アドレナリンずっと流して
Adrenalin always pumping,
僕の方がオーバーヒートしそう
it'll be me that overheats!
爆発して灰になっても
Even if I explode and turn into ash,
このままだと笑ってるね きっと
I bet I'll be laughing as I am now.
街を追い越して この世の果てまで
Throughout the city to the ends of the earth,
ぶっ飛ばして心中しよう さあ手を伸ばして!
let's drive madly and perish together, throw up your arms!
地平線に届くように限界まで切り切ってくれる
To reach the horizon you've got to break down the barrier!
Woh! Clash! Into the rolling morning
Flash! I'm in the coolest driver's high
最高のフィナーレを! Yeah!
This is the best finale ever! Yeah!
もう数えるくらいで僕らは消し失せて真摯な朝が来るね
Soon enough we'll be no more and a pitch black morning will come.
お気に入りの服に さあ着がえたなら駆け出して!
So get in your favorite clothes and we'll take off!
あきれるほど声を上げて大気圏を突破しようぜ
Raise your voice as high as you can and break through the atmosphere!
Woh! Clash! Into the rolling morning
Flash! I'm in the coolest driver's high
鋼の翼で 駆けぬけよ時間切れまで
With steel wings, until my time's up let's keep breaking through,
生まれつきのスピード狂なのさ
'cuz I was born speed crazy!
もう数えるくらいで僕らは消し失せて真摯な朝が来るね
Soon enough we'll be no more and a pitch black morning will come,
お気に入りの服に さきがえたなら駆け出して!
so get in your favorite clothes and we'll take off!
あきれるほど声を上げて大気圏を突破しようぜ
Raise your voice as high as you can and break through the atmosphere!
Woh! Clash! Into the rolling morning
Flash! I'm in the coolest driver's high
熱くなった銀のメタリックハート
My silver, metallic heart heated up,
導火線に火をつけてあげる
I'll light the fuse for you.
不思議なほどハイな気分さ 砂塵を巻き上げて行こう
I feel so high it's strange, let's kick some dust up.
悲鳴をまじらせ暴走する鼓動 目の前にはミサイルの雨
My recklessly beating pulse blends with the shrieks, a rain of missiles ahead.
アドレナリンずーっと流して 僕の方がオーバーヒートしそう
My adrenaline's flowing so much I might overheat.
爆発して灰になっても このままだと笑ってるね きっと
Even if I explode to ashes, I'll still be smiling just like this.
Woh! Clash! Into the rolling morning / Flash! I'm in the coolest driver's high
街を追い越して この世の果てまで ぶっ飛ばして
Passing through the town to the end of the world, let's blast off!
ライセレまた青い空へ
Flying once again to the blue sky!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
今日はスワちゃんと、はい！相棒ちゃんに来てもらいました！
Today, Suwa-chan and... yes! My partner came along!
おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations!
ここでのね、エピソードといえば
Speaking of episodes here...
うすうす分かったよ、私のおうすうすは
I kind of figured it out, my...
これとかもあったしね
There was stuff like this too, right?
まあなんとなくなんだけどね
Well, sort of, you know.
これGTAでね、ギャングと警察でバチバチやり合ってたからさ
In GTA, the gang and police were going at it hard.
今回ドライバーズハイを一緒に歌わせていただきました
We got to sing "Driver's High" together this time!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
もうだいぶ、だいぶ昨年の恩恵になりましたよ
It's already been a huge help since last year!
いっぱい企画もやったりとかもしたしね
We did lots of projects and stuff too.
そうだよ！二人とも、この後なんか色々ゲームやったもん
That's right! Afterwards you guys played various games.
覚えてる？あのとんでも、なんか野生の味を知りさにさ
Do you remember? Wanting to know that wild taste...
野生味のあるワイルドな小林さんに会ったんだよ
Meeting wild Kobayashi-san with a wild flavor!
なんかラックラーメンみたいなね、落としそうかも
Like luck ramen, might drop it.
じゃあ小林ちゃんもワイルドなのやろう、寿司とか肉以外食べテエわ
Then Kobayashi-chan should do wild stuff too, I wanna eat sushi or meat.
マジでやべえぞ
Seriously dangerous!
マジでやばいぞ、ズズズって、しばらく磯の味抜けないから
Seriously dangerous, slurping that ocean taste won't leave for a while!
なんでも食べられちゃうよ、コオロギとかもね
You can eat anything, even crickets!
そういうきっかけにもっともっと今年はもっともっとって
As a catalyst for this year, let's do even more!
いっぱい食べたら嬉しいなってことでよろしくお願いします！
We'd be happy if you eat a lot, so please look after us!
みんなも誘ってよ！誘おうよ！
Invite everyone too! Let's invite them!
不思議のね、あの、おばけ屋敷行こうよ
Let's go to the mystery haunted house.
いや、やだ！なんで？なんで？流されないから私
No way! Why? Why? I won't get swept away!
おばけ屋敷行こうよ、なんでなんの？
Let's go to the haunted house, why not?
なんで？でも不思議って限定なんだよ？一番怖いって聞くじゃん
Why? But it's limited to mystery, right? It's said to be the scariest!
こういうおめでたい場で知るって聞いたら行けるかなって思ったけど
I thought if I heard it at such a celebratory place I could go...
ご飯から始めて、謎解きとかもあるね
Starting with meals, then riddle solving too.
なるほどね！なるほどね！
I see! I see!
ということですごいもっと本当は喋ってたいんだけど時間が足りないや
So, I actually want to talk more, but we're out of time.
やばいやばい！わきちゃん今年もよろしくお願いします！お疲れ様です！
Oh no! Waki-chan, please look after us again this year!
本当に！おめでとう！ありがとうございます！
Congratulations! Thank you!
またね！バイバーイ！
See you! Bye-bye!
え、どっち？どっち？じゃあこっち行こう！こっち行こう！
Let's go this way! Let's go this way!
Hi rose and girls
絢爛の花園 上層の高さを
In the gorgeous garden, the height of the upper layers...
まだ測ってんの？未だ待ってんの？
Are you still measuring? Are you still waiting?
違う乗ってんの？ 音に乗ってんの？
No, you're riding it? Riding on the sound?
人生は薔薇色 信じたそう何回も
Life is rose-colored, believed so how many times?
視野濁ってんの？ お茶濁してんの？
Is your field of view blurred? Are you dodging the question?
違う持ってんの？ 違い持ってんの？
No, you're holding it? Holding a different one?
違う持ってんの 願い持ってんの
You've got it wrong, you hold a wish.
何処へ行けば見える 叢
Where must I go to see the thicket?
為せば成るがシンプル 棘
"Where there's a will, there's a way" is a simple thorn.
逃げて 逃げて 逃げて 森奥へ
Run, run, run, deep into the forest!
Rose and girls
Oh my gosh!
茨ばっかばっかの世界だから
Because this world is full of thorns,
時折夢見霞むけど
though I sometimes dream in a haze,
でもね待った待ったって 意味ないから
waiting and waiting is pointless, so
無垢なルートに 囚われないように 何色にでもなれるから
I won't be trapped by a pure route, I can become any color!
Hi rose and girls
uh uh uh
Na na na na
Hi rose and girls
今宵歌うよ 野に咲く私を見てて
Tonight I'll sing, watch me bloom in the field!
知恵の果実を
Nibbling lightly on
淡々と噛じるの
the fruit of wisdom,
意味分かんの 味わってんの
do you understand the meaning, are you savoring it?
これが合ってんのか 分かっていたいの
Is this right? I want to know for sure.
背に堕落エンド これからでしょ
A downfall ending, this is just the beginning!
咲ければ全免除 闇ゲット アンネット 桟機を全Betと
Total exemption if I bloom, get the darkness, get the net!
皆いる？今マイル？良ければ教えてくれアイルー
Is everyone here? Are you with me? Tell me, Ailou!
転んでも大丈夫 私がいる
Even if you fall, it's okay, I am here.
誰も彼も同じコーデ
Everyone wearing the same outfit,
来る日来る日もお勤め
working day in and day out.
逃げた 逃げた 逃げた 虚空の方へ
Run away, run away, run away into the void!
桃源があるから
Because there is a Peach Blossom Spring!
茨ばっかばっかの世界だから
Because this world is full of thorns,
時折夢見霞むけど
though I sometimes dream in a haze,
でもね待った待ったって 意味ないから
waiting and waiting is pointless, so
無垢なルートに 囚われないように 何色にでもなれるから
I won't be trapped by a pure route, I can become any color!
Hi rose and girls
uh uh uh
na na na na
Hi rose and girls
君に歌うよ 虚に咲く私を見てて
I'll sing to you, watch me bloom in the emptiness!
アローナ！今を初披露した新曲『異薔薇』どうだったかな？
Allo! How did you like my newly performed single, "Ibara"?
この後24時頃から配信サービスでも聴けるようになるので、ぜひたくさん聴いて感想をどしどしSNSに投稿してください！
You'll be able to stream it at midnight, so post your thoughts!
ミニ行くよ？
Shall we head over?
ねえねえ、そこの君、チャンネル登録ってもうした？
Hey you right there, have you subscribed yet?
うん、まだだよね？じゃあチャンネル登録ポチ、高評価もポチ、ついでに通知もオンポチ！
Then smash that subscribe button, like, and turn on notifications!
ということで、まだの人よろしくお願いします。
If you haven't yet, I'd appreciate your support.
ちなみに、この後22時30分からメンバー限定アフターライブをやっちゃうので、メンバーシップの登録をしてくれた方忘れないでぜひこのままレッツゴーしましょう！待っててね！
Members-only after-live is at 22:30 tonight, don't miss it!
からの！アキ・ローゼンタール生誕祭2025記念グッズ発売いたしまーす！待ってたよね？
And now! My 2025 Birthday merchandise is on sale!
ということで早速紹介していきましょう！ラインナップはこちら！
Let's introduce them right away, here is the lineup!
今回のライブコンセプト『ユアートルカラス』を主題に、雪子先生に描いていただきました！異世界の世界観あるお花屋さんのようなをイメージしております。
Based on our live concept "Yuatokarasu," Yukiko-sensei drew this!
こちら！キービジュアルが大きくプリントされたワイドラバーマット！大きくて使いやすいラバーマット、いろんな使い道ができると思います。飾るもよし、使うもよし、あなたのパソコン周りにぜひ彩りを添えてください！
A wide rubber mat with the key visual! Add color to your PC!
次は、こちら！なんとついにでた！アキ・ローゼンタールとおそろいフルグラフィックTシャツ！アキロゼのゲーミング衣装のインナーとおそろいのTシャツになっています。ゲーミングパーカーを買ってくれた方はこれとこれセットにしちゃうとメンツいい感じなんじゃないの？
Next is the matching full graphic T-shirt with the gaming inner wear!
次は、こちら！アキロゼのヘッドセンサーヘアクリップ！ありそうでなかったアキロゼの身につけているグッズ！はい、あなたのお手元に届いちゃいまーす！アキロゼのヘッドセンサーを再現したヘアクリップになってるんだけど、髪を留めるのに使ってもよし、いろんなものに挟んでもよし、身につけてもよし、置いといてもよし、アキロゼがねそこにい
And the head sensor hair clips, recreating my head sensor!
じゃないかと思わせる痕跡になると思うので、
because it leaves traces that make people think you might be one,
是非いろんなね、楽しい遊び方をして下さい！いっぱいいっぱいゲットしてね！
please enjoy playing with it in various fun ways! Be sure to get lots of them!
次はアキロゼぬいぐるみカードホルダー！
Next up is the Aki Rosenthal Plush Card Holder!
アキロゼの顔がついたカードケースになっています。
It's a card case featuring Aki Rosenthal's face.
めっちゃかわいい！
It's super cute!
お気に入りのカードや、このあと紹介する特典チェキも入れられちゃいます。
You can put your favorite cards or the bonus チェキ we'll introduce later inside.
さらに今年の誕生日シチュエーションボイスも出てます！
Furthermore, this year's birthday situation voice pack is also available!
「あまあみみかき」ボイス、だいふくアキロゼが考えて頑張って撮りました！
The "Sweet Ear-Cleaning" voice—Daifuku Aki Rosenthal thought hard and worked hard to record!
ていうか楽しんで撮りました！そしてなんと今回はフルセット特典もあります！
Well, actually she had fun recording it! And what's more, this time there are also full-set bonuses!
フルセット購入特典はASMR特典ボイス、タイトルは「アイス食べよ♡」、そういうことです。
The full-set purchase bonus is an ASMR bonus voice titled "Let's Eat Ice Cream ♡". That's what it is.
そしてもうひとつ購入特典は、サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードです。
And another purchase bonus is a bromid card styled like a チェキ with a signature.
こちら箔押し複製サイン入り、是非カードケースに入れて持ち歩いて欲しいなって。
This one features foil-stamped replica signatures; I really want you to put it in your card case and carry it around.
え？直筆サインが欲しい？もう、なんとあります！
Eh? You want a handwritten signature? Well, surprise, we actually have it!
そんなあなたに数量限定バージョンを是非ゲットしてください！
For those of you, please be sure to get the quantity-limited version!
数に限りがあるのでお見逃しなく！
There's a limited quantity so don't miss out!
このあと22時20分ショップオープン予定なので、会員登録とか済ませてない人は準備して待っててね！
The shop is scheduled to open at 22:20 just after this, so if you haven't finished member registration yet, get ready and wait!
概要欄をチェックチェック！
Check, check the description box!
そして今回フルセットをご購入いただいた方に、昨年9月に発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚特典として付きます。
And for those who purchase the full set this time, as a bonus, you'll get one card usable in the Hololive Official Card Game released last September.
推しアピールできるキーカード！推しほろめんカードです。
A key card to show off your oshi! It's an Oshi Horomen card.
カードの詳細や遊び方についてもホームページで確認してね！カードは日本語版のみになりますのでご容赦ください。
Please check the homepage for details on the cards and how to play! Please note that the cards will be in Japanese only.
ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップでご購入された方のみ対象となりますのでご注意ください。
Please note that this is only applicable to those who purchased at the Hololive Production Official Shop.
以上誕生日記念グッズでした！
That's all for the birthday commemorative goods!
このあとメンバー限定のアフターライブもあるので、よろしければメンバー登録もよろしくおねがいします！
There's also a member-only after-live right after this, so if you'd like, please consider member registration as well!
それでは、ライブの締めくくりエンディングがありますので、是非最後まで見ていってくださいね！今日のライブの感想も是非たくさんつぶやいてね！
Now then, there's the wrapping-up ending of the live, so please be sure to watch until the very end! And please tweet a lot of your thoughts on today's live!
それでは、ユワテルカラーズのエンディングご覧ください。
Now then, please enjoy the ending by Yuwateru Colors.
モノクロの世界に囚われてしまっていた彼女の心は
Trapped in a monochrome world, her heart
様々な花達や、お客さんとの触れ合いを経て
through various flowers and interactions with customers
当たり前の日常はいつも自分のそばにあって、何よりも大切、ということに気づきました。
realized that ordinary daily life is always by her side, and is more precious than anything else.
そんな大切な、たくさんの思い出の中で
Amidst all those precious, numerous memories,
笑顔をもらっていたのは自分だけじゃなく、自分もみんなを笑顔にしていたことを、彼女は知りました。
she came to know that she wasn't the only one receiving smiles, but that she too was making everyone smile.
いろんな色があって、それが自分らしくて良いんだと
That there are various colors, and that being true to oneself is fine,
自分自身の魅力を認めることができました。
she was able to acknowledge her own charm.
そしてついに彼女は、今まで以上の輝きを取り戻すことができたのです。
And finally, she was able to regain a sparkle greater than ever before.
このお話は決して、彼女だけの物語ではありません。
This story is by no means her story alone.
そう、花屋はいつでも、ここにある、あなたの心の中に。
Yes, the flower shop is always right here, in your heart.
Your true colors Aki Rosenthal 2023 Birthday LIVE
Your true colors - Aki Rosenthal 2023 Birthday LIVE